const msword_quiz =  [
    {
      "question": "How many different positions can you set for drop cap ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "ड्रॉप कैप के लिए आप कितने अलग-अलग पद सेट कर सकते हैं",

      "option1" : "a)   1",
      "hindi1"  : "",

      "option2" : "b)   2",
      "hindi2"  : "",

      "option3" : "c)   4",
      "hindi3"  : "",

      "option4" : "d)   6",
      "hindi4"  : "",

      "answer"  : "b)   2",
      "hindiAns"  : "",
    },
    {
      "question": "How many ways you can save a document ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "आप किसी दस्तावेज़ को कितने तरीकों से सहेज सकते हैं",

      "option1" : "a)   3",
      "hindi1"  : "",

      "option2" : "b)   4",
      "hindi2"  : "",

      "option3" : "c)   5",
      "hindi3"  : "",

      "option4" : "d)   6",
      "hindi4"  : "",

      "answer"  : "a)   3",
      "hindiAns"  : "",
    },
    {
      "question": "Single spacing in MS Word document causes - point line spacing ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "एमएस वर्ड दस्तावेज़ में एकल रिक्ति बिंदु रेखा रिक्ति का कारण बनती है",

      "option1" : "a)   10",
      "hindi1"  : "",

      "option2" : "b)   12",
      "hindi2"  : "",

      "option3" : "c)   14",
      "hindi3"  : "",

      "option4" : "d)   16",
      "hindi4"  : "",

      "answer"  : "b)   12",
      "hindiAns"  : "",
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the default number of lines to drop for drop cap ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "ड्रॉप कैप के लिए ड्रॉप करने वाली लाइनों की डिफ़ॉल्ट संख्या क्या है?",

      "option1" : "a)   3",
      "hindi1"  : "",

      "option2" : "b)   10",
      "hindi2"  : "",

      "option3" : "c)   15",
      "hindi3"  : "",

      "option4" : "d)   20",
      "hindi4"  : "",

      "answer"  : "a)   3",
      "hindiAns"  : "",
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the maximum number of lines you can set for a drop cap ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "ड्रॉप कैप के लिए आप अधिकतम कितनी लाइनें सेट कर सकते हैं ?",

      "option1" : "a)   3",
      "hindi1"  : "",

      "option2" : "b)   10",
      "hindi2"  : "",

      "option3" : "c)   15",
      "hindi3"  : "",

      "option4" : "d)   20",
      "hindi4"  : "",

      "answer"  : "b)   10",
      "hindiAns"  : "",
    },
    {
      "question": "How many column can you insert in a word document in maximum ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "आप किसी शब्द दस्तावेज़ में अधिकतम कितने स्तंभ सम्मिलित कर सकते हैं ?",

      "option1" : "a)   35",
      "hindi1"  : "",

      "option2" : "b)   45",
      "hindi2"  : "",

      "option3" : "c)   55",
      "hindi3"  : "",

      "option4" : "d)   65",
      "hindi4"  : "",

      "answer"  : "b)   45",
      "hindiAns"  : "",
    },
    {
      "question": "In a document, What is the maximum number of columns that can be inserted in MS-Word Table ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "किसी दस्तावेज़ में, MS-Word तालिका में सम्मिलित किए जा सकने वाले स्तंभों की अधिकतम संख्या क्या है ?",

      "option1" : "a)   35",
      "hindi1"  : "",

      "option2" : "b)   15",
      "hindi2"  : "",

      "option3" : "c)   63",
      "hindi3"  : "",

      "option4" : "d)   65",
      "hindi4"  : "",

      "answer"  : "c)   63",
      "hindiAns"  : "",
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the maximum scale percentage available in scale drop down box ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "स्केल ड्रॉप डाउन बॉक्स में उपलब्ध अधिकतम स्केल प्रतिशत क्या है ?",

      "option1" : "a)   500",
      "hindi1"  : "",

      "option2" : "b)   200",
      "hindi2"  : "",

      "option3" : "c)   100",
      "hindi3"  : "",

      "option4" : "d)   90",
      "hindi4"  : "",

      "answer"  : "b)   200",
      "hindiAns"  : "",
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the maximum font size you can apply for any character ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "अधिकतम फ़ॉन्ट आकार क्या है जिसे आप किसी भी वर्ण के लिए लागू कर सकते हैं ?",

      "option1" : "a)   163",
      "hindi1"  : "",

      "option2" : "b)   1638",
      "hindi2"  : "",

      "option3" : "c)   16038",
      "hindi3"  : "",

      "option4" : "d)   16",
      "hindi4"  : "",

      "answer"  : "b)   1638",
      "hindiAns"  : "",
    },
    {
      "question": "Word by default, places a tab step at every_mark on the ruler ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "डिफ़ॉल्ट रूप से शब्द, शासक पर प्रत्येक चिह्न पर एक टैब चरण रखता है ?",

      'option1' : 'a)   2.5"',
      'hindi1'  : '',

      'option2' : 'b)   .5"',
      'hindi2'  : '',

      'option3' : 'c)   .75"',
      'hindi3'  : '',

      'option4' : 'd)   .1"',
      'hindi4'  : '',

      'answer'  : 'b)   .5"',
      'hindiAns'  : '',
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the default file extension for all word documents ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "सभी शब्द दस्तावेज़ों के लिए डिफ़ॉल्ट फ़ाइल एक्सटेंशन क्या है ?",

      "option1" : "a)   txt",
      "hindi1"  : "",

      "option2" : "b)   word",
      "hindi2"  : "",

      "option3" : "c)   docs",
      "hindi3"  : "",

      "option4" : "d)   docx",
      "hindi4"  : "",

      "answer"  : "d)   docx",
      "hindiAns"  : "",
    },
    {
      "question": "The file type_indicates the file is a word document ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "फ़ाइल प्रकार इंगित करता है कि फ़ाइल एक शब्द दस्तावेज़ है ?",

      "option1" : "a)   .msw",
      "hindi1"  : "",

      "option2" : "b)   .wor",
      "hindi2"  : "",

      "option3" : "c)   .wrd",
      "hindi3"  : "",

      "option4" : "d)   .doc",
      "hindi4"  : "",

      "answer"  : "d)   .doc",
      "hindiAns"  : "",
    },
    {
      "question": "How much space in minimum must be provided between columns ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "कॉलम के बीच न्यूनतम कितना स्थान प्रदान किया जाना चाहिए ?",

      'option1' : 'a)   0"',
      'hindi1'  : '',

      'option2' : 'b)   0.5"',
      'hindi2'  : '',

      'option3' : 'c)   .1"',
      'hindi3'  : '',

      'option4' : 'd)   .1.5"',
      'hindi4'  : '',

      'answer'  : 'a)   0"',
      'hindiAns'  : '',
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the smallest width of column ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "स्तंभ की सबसे छोटी चौड़ाई क्या है ?",

      'option1' : 'a)   0"',
      'hindi1'  : '',

      'option2' : 'b)   0.5"',
      'hindi2'  : '',

      'option3' : 'c)   1"',
      'hindi3'  : '',

      'option4' : 'd)   .1.5"',
      'hindi4'  : '',

      'answer'  : 'd)   1.5"',
      'hindiAns'  : '',
    },
    {
      "question": "By default, your document print with ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "डिफ़ॉल्ट रूप से, आपका दस्तावेज़ प्रिंट किसके साथ मुद्रित होता है ?",

      "option1" : "a)   1 inch top and bottom margins",
      "hindi1"  : "1 इंच ऊपर और नीचे मार्जिन",

      "option2" : "b)   A portrait orientation",
      "hindi2"  : "एक चित्र अभिविन्यास",

      "option3" : "c)   1.25 inches left and right margins",
      "hindi3"  : "1.25 इंच बाएं और दाएं मार्जिन",

      "option4" : "d)   All of the above",
      "hindi4"  : "उपरोक्त सभी",

      "answer"  : "b)   A portrait orientation",
      "hindiAns"  : "एक चित्र अभिविन्यास",
    },
    {
      "question": "Word is present to use standard 8.5 by 11 inch paper with margins ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "वर्ड मार्जिन के साथ मानक 8.5 बाय 11 इंच पेपर का उपयोग करने के लिए मौजूद है ?",

      "option1" : "a)   1 inch left, right, top and bottom",
      "hindi1"  : "1 इंच बाएं , दाएं , ऊपर और नीचे",

      "option2" : "b)   1.25 inch left, right top and bottom",
      "hindi2"  : "1.25 इंच बाएं , दाएं ऊपर और नीचे",

      "option3" : "c)   1.25 inch left and right margins and depend button",
      "hindi3"  : "1.25 इंच बाएं और दाएं मार्जिन और निर्भर बटन",

      "option4" : "d)   1 inch left and right margins and 1.25 inch top and bottom",
      "hindi4"  : "1 इंच बाएं और दाएं मार्जिन और 1.25 इंच ऊपर और नीचे",

      "answer"  : "b)   1.25 inch left, right top and bottom",
      "hindiAns"  : "1.25 इंच बाएं , दाएं ऊपर और नीचे",
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the default left margin in ms word 2003 document ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "MS Word 2003 दस्तावेज़ में डिफ़ॉल्ट बाएँ मार्जिन क्या है? ?",

      'option1' : 'a)   1"',
      'hindi1'  : '',

      'option2' : 'b)   1.25"',
      'hindi2'  : '',

      'option3' : 'c)   1.5"',
      'hindi3'  : '',

      'option4' : 'd)   2"',
      'hindi4'  : '',

      'answer'  : 'b)   1.25"',
      'hindiAns'  : '',
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the smallest and largest font size available in font size tool on formatting toolbar ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "स्वरूपण उपकरण पट्टी पर फ़ॉन्ट आकार उपकरण में उपलब्ध सबसे छोटा और सबसे बड़ा फ़ॉन्ट आकार क्या है ?",

      "option1" : "a)   8 and 72",
      "hindi1"  : "8 और 72",

      "option2" : "b)   8 and 64",
      "hindi2"  : "8 और 64",

      "option3" : "c)   12 and 72",
      "hindi3"  : "12 और 72",

      "option4" : "d)   None of above",
      "hindi4"  : "उपरोक्त में से कोई नहीं",

      "answer"  : "b)   8 and 72",
      "hindiAns"  : "8 और 72",
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the default font size of a new word document based on normal template in MS word 2003 ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "MS Word 2003 में सामान्य टेम्पलेट के आधार पर किसी नए शब्द दस्तावेज़ का डिफ़ॉल्ट फ़ॉन्ट आकार क्या है ?",

      "option1" : "a)   10pt",
      "hindi1"  : "",

      "option2" : "b)   12pt",
      "hindi2"  : "",

      "option3" : "c)   14pt",
      "hindi3"  : "",

      "option4" : "d)   16pt",
      "hindi4"  : "",

      "answer"  : "b)   12pt",
      "hindiAns"  : "",
    },
    {
      "question": "The minimum number of rows and columns in MS-Word document is ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "MS-Word दस्तावेज़ में पंक्तियों और स्तंभों की न्यूनतम संख्या क्या है ?",

      "option1" : "a)   1 and 1",
      "hindi1"  : "1 और 1",

      "option2" : "b)   2 and 1",
      "hindi2"  : "2 और 1",

      "option3" : "c)   2 and 2",
      "hindi3"  : "2 और 2",

      "option4" : "d)   None of above",
      "hindi4"  : "उपरोक्त में से कोई नहीं",

      "answer"  : "a)   1 and 1",
      "hindiAns"  : "1 और 1",
    },
    {
      "question": "Pressing F8 key for three times select ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "F8 कुंजी को तीन बार दबाने का चयन करें ?",

      "option1" : "a)   A word",
      "hindi1"  : "एक शब्द",

      "option2" : "b)   A sentence",
      "hindi2"  : "एक वाक्य",

      "option3" : "c)   A paragraph",
      "hindi3"  : "एक अनुच्छेद",

      "option4" : "d)   entire document",
      "hindi4"  : "पूरा दस्तावेज़",

      "answer"  : "b)   A sentence",
      "hindiAns"  : "एक वाक्य",
    },
    {
      "question": "What do you call a collection of character and paragraph formatting commands ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "आप वर्ण और अनुच्छेद स्वरूपण आदेशों का संग्रह क्या कहते हैं ?",

      "option1" : "a)   A style",
      "hindi1"  : "एक शैली",

      "option2" : "b)   A template",
      "hindi2"  : "एक टेम्पलेट",

      "option3" : "c)   A boilerplate",
      "hindi3"  : "एक बॉयलरप्लेट",

      "option4" : "d)   None of the above",
      "hindi4"  : "उपरोक्त में से कोई नहीं",

      "answer"  : "b)   A style",
      "hindiAns"  : "एक शैली",
    },
    {
      "question": "What is document outline view ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "दस्तावेज़ रूपरेखा दृश्य क्या है ?",

      "option1" : "a)   A preview in a full screen",
      "hindi1"  : "एक पूर्ण स्क्रीन में एक पूर्वावलोकन",

      "option2" : "b)   A preview with margins",
      "hindi2"  : "मार्जिन के साथ एक पूर्वावलोकन",

      "option3" : "c)   A view with a margins and gutter",
      "hindi3"  : "मार्जिन और गटर के साथ एक दृश्य",

      "option4" : "d)   A view with a structure of heading at various levels",
      "hindi4"  : "विभिन्न स्तरों पर शीर्ष की संरचना के साथ एक दृश्य",

      "answer"  : "d)   A view with a structure of heading at various levels",
      "hindiAns"  : "विभिन्न स्तरों पर शीर्ष की संरचना के साथ एक दृश्य",
    },
    {
      "question": "Ctrl+Z ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "",

      "option1" : "a)   Undo the last action",
      "hindi1"  : "अंतिम क्रिया को पूर्ववत करें",

      "option2" : "b)   Redo the last action",
      "hindi2"  : "अंतिम क्रिया को फिर से करें",

      "option3" : "c)   Add the new page",
      "hindi3"  : "नया पृष्ठ जोड़ें",

      "option4" : "d)   Paste the contents clipboard",
      "hindi4"  : "सामग्री क्लिपबोर्ड चिपकाएँ",

      "answer"  : "a)   Undo the last action",
      "hindiAns"  : "अंतिम क्रिया को पूर्ववत करें",
    },
    {
      "question": "The ____ in the resume wizard dialog box indicates the wizard is ready to create the document ?",
      "hindiquestion" : "रिज्यूमे विज़ार्ड संवाद बॉक्स में _____ इंगित करता है कि विज़ार्ड दस्तावेज़ बनाने के लिए तैयार है",

      "option1" : "a)   Start panel",
      "hindi1"  : "प्रारंभ पैनल",

      "option2" : "b)   Address panel",
      "hindi2"  : "पता पैनल",

      "option3" : "c)   Add/Sort Heading panel",
      "hindi3"  : "शीर्षक पैनल जोड़ें/सॉर्ट करें",

      "option4" : "d)   Finish panel",
      "hindi4"  : "समापन पैनल",

      "answer"  : "d)   Finish panel",
      "hindiAns"  : "समापन पैनल",
    }
    /*
    {
      "question": "26.     What does Ctrl + = key effect ?",
      "option1" : "a)   Superscript",
      "option2" : "b)   Subscript",
      "option3" : "c)   All caps",
      "option4" : "d)   Shadow",
      "answer"  : "b)   Subscript"
    },
    {
      "question": "27.     The word wrap feature ?",
      "option1" : "a)   Automatically move text to the next line when necessary",
      "option2" : "b)   Appears at the bottom of the document",
      "option3" : "c)   All you to type over text",
      "option4" : "d)   It is the short horizontal line",
      "answer"  : "a)   Automatically move text to the next line when necessary"
    },
    {
      "question": "28.     How can you make the selected character superscriptd ?",
      "option1" : "a)   Ctrl + =",
      "option2" : "b)   Ctrl + Shift + =",
      "option3" : "c)   Alt + Ctrl + shift + =",
      "option4" : "d)   None of Above",
      "answer"  : "b)   Ctrl + Shift + ="
    },
    {
      "question": "29.     When typing in a word field manually, what must you press to insert the code's braces ?",
      "option1" : "a)   Ctrl + F6",
      "option2" : "b)   Ctrl + F9",
      "option3" : "c)   Alt + F9",
      "option4" : "d)   Shift + F12",
      "answer"  : "b)   Ctrl + F9"
    },
    {
      "question": "30.     What is the shortcut key to open the open dialog box ?",
      "option1" : "a)   F12",
      "option2" : "b)   Shift + F12",
      "option3" : "c)   Alt + F12",
      "option4" : "d)   Ctrl + F12",
      "answer"  : "d)   Ctrl + F12"
    },
    {
      "question": "31.     What is the shortcut key to split a table ?",
      "option1" : "a)   Ctrl + Alt + Enter",
      "option2" : "b)   Ctrl + Shift + Enter",
      "option3" : "c)   Alt + Shift + Enter",
      "option4" : "d)   Alt + Space + Enter",
      "answer"  : "b)   Ctrl + Shift + Enter"
    },
    {
      "question": "32.     Which key is use to increase left indent ?",
      "option1" : "a)   Ctrl + i",
      "option2" : "b)   Ctrl + m",
      "option3" : "c)   Alt + i",
      "option4" : "d)   F10",
      "answer"  : "b)   Ctrl + m"
    },
    {
      "question": "33.     When the same word is used in multiple locatons or a word is used to that was not quite appropriate, a thesaurus can used to look up an ___ or a word similar in meaning ?",
      "option1" : "a)   Synonym",
      "option2" : "b)   Homonym",
      "option3" : "c)   Antonym",
      "option4" : "d)   Metronym",
      "answer"  : "a)   Synonym"
    },
    {
      "question": "34.     How many different documents you can open at one time ?",
      "option1" : "a)   No more than three",
      "option2" : "b)   Only one",
      "option3" : "c)   As many as your computer memory will hold",
      "option4" : "d)   As many as your taskbar can display",
      "answer"  : "c)   As many as your computer memory will hold."
    },
    {
      "question": "35.     Which of the following is the second step in creating a macro ?",
      "option1" : "a)   Start recording",
      "option2" : "b)   Using your mouse or keyboard, perform that task you want to automate",
      "option3" : "c)   Assign a keyboard shortcut to the macro ",
      "option4" : "d)   Give the macro a name",
      "answer"  : "d)   Give the macro a name"
    },
    {
      "question": "36.      When assigning a shortcut key to a symbol, you should always try to select a key or key combination that is :",
      "option1" : "a)   Unassigned",
      "option2" : "b)   Located on the ten key pad selection of your keyboard",
      "option3" : "c)   Assigned to another task",
      "option4" : "d)   None of the above",
      "answer"  : "a)   Unassigned"
    },
    {
      "question": "37.     Which feature is used to replace straight quotes with smart quotes as yuou typw ?",
      "option1" : "a)   Fixed column width",
      "option2" : "b)   Autofit to contents",
      "option3" : "c)   Autofit to windows",
      "option4" : "d)   Autofit to column",
      "answer"  : "d)   Autofit to column."
    },
    {
      "question": "38.     When you click on file menu in word 2010, it open  ?",
      "option1" : "a)   File menu",
      "option2" : "b)   File command",
      "option3" : "c)   Backstage view",
      "option4" : "d)   File Ribbon",
      "answer"  : "c)   Backstage view"
    },
    {
      "question": "39.     Tab stop position cannot be  ?",
      "option1" : "a)   No more than three",
      "option2" : "b)   Only one",
      "option3" : "c)   As many as your computer memory will hold",
      "option4" : "d)   As many as your taskbar can display",
      "answer"  : "c)   As many as your computer memory will hold."
    },
    {
      "question": "40.     Ctrl + B ?",
      "option1" : "a)   Search the selected text",
      "option2" : "b)   Paste the selected text",
      "option3" : "c)   Bold the selected text",
      "option4" : "d)   Open the specified file",
      "answer"  : "c)   Bold the selected text"
    },
  */
  ];

export default msword_quiz;